Hello everyone, welcome back to to this another new tutorial topic. So today here,
I can create for the MySQL drop table. It is important operation when managing our database
scheme. Okay, so first of all here, I can simply just define for the MySQL drop table statement,
and here it is completely use the MySQL used to delete the existing table and critical operation.
So it is essential for understanding for how it works. Okay, so now just explore for here the basic
example. Okay, so first of all here, I create the dropping the simple table. Okay, so first of all,
here I can create for the drop table statement. Okay, so define for here the drop table statement
to drop the table. Okay, so define for here completely table and in the operation,
completely now successful. So just select and then execute and just do it and you can see here
in this operation completely successful and the MySQL return the confirmation message for
in the message and this including the table has been completely blocked. Okay, so now just verify and
simply open this another new and you can try select then multiplication sign and use the problem
time here you can define this is the implies table. Okay, so now for quickly create this statement
and now executing and you can see here the invalid name for the recommended for the employees
table. Okay, so I hope you understand this and next step here, we are dropping the table if
exist again. So now just write and first of all, I can use the exist plus table. So now just go
here drop table and just type. So suppose I can use then if xt okay, so I can check again
xt a for the table name supports define perfectly this product stable. Okay, and here in the drop table
then the product only exist if the table does not exist. Okay, so now here I can select
for execute and you can see here this the MySQL is returned a message indicating that no table
was here drop. So just go here and change from the employee and inside the product table. Okay,
so just select perfectly and then execute and now you can see here invalid product and because
you have perfectly dropped this product table. Okay, so here is for another drop table. So dropping
the table with the point. Okay, so now just go here and change for the product and now here
create for the foreign key the order stable. Okay, so do you find perfectly this order stable and
this drop statement to denote the order table and the table has a foreign key relationship
with other tables. Okay, now here this is completely used and order and drop and select and execute
and you can see here my SQL will automatically drop the associate columns and here it is completely
drop the table. Okay, so here just I can check so remove this product and here I can insert the
order stable. So first of all select and release the queue and you can see here completely
dropped the order table one. Okay, right, in this session is completely dropped for the perfectly
and drop the free table and completely avoid you and trying to drop the table in the MySQL with
some practical example. Okay, so I hope you perfectly understand this session. So now thank you
for watching and happy coding. Okay.